<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" > 

	<channel>
		<title>R-Project News</title>
		<atom:link href="https://user2023.r-project.org/feed/gn" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<link>https://user2023.r-project.org/</link>
		<description></description>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 06:52:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod> hourly </sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency> 1 </sy:updateFrequency>
		<atom:link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
		<generator>GN Publisher v1.5.10 https://wordpress.org/plugins/gn-publisher/</generator>

		<item>
			<title>The iPhone 15 Launch: Release Date, Pricing, and Innovative Features</title>
			<link>https://user2023.r-project.org/news/tech/the-iphone-15-launch-release-date-pricing-and-innovative-features/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 06:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://user2023.r-project.org/?p=27</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[Get ready, folks! Apple is about to drop some serious tech magic on us. Picture...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://user2023.r-project.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/iPhone-15-Launch.webp" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>Get ready, folks! Apple is about to drop some serious tech magic on us. Picture this: the new iPhone 15 and iPhone 15 Pro, shining like stars in the smartphone galaxy. But that&#8217;s not all; Apple&#8217;s got some tricks up its sleeve for the Apple Watch too.</p>



<p>So, here&#8217;s the scoop: Apple&#8217;s &#8220;Wanderlust&#8221; event is set to kick off at the legendary Steve Jobs Theatre in California. It&#8217;s a big deal because the smartphone market has been as slow as a snail&#8217;s crawl lately, and Apple&#8217;s feeling the heat after a summer of slumping iPhone sales.</p>



<p>But let&#8217;s not dwell on the past; let&#8217;s dive into the future. The iPhone 15 launch is happening at 6 pm BST on Tuesday, September 12, or 10 am California time. Mark your calendars and grab your popcorn because you can catch the livestream on YouTube.</p>



<p>Now, the big question on everyone&#8217;s mind is, when can you actually get your hands on the iPhone 15? Well, usually, Apple announces its new toys on a Tuesday, and pre-orders open later in the week. For the iPhone 15, you&#8217;ll want to keep your eyes peeled on Friday, September 15. The official release and party with the networks will start on Friday, September 22.</p>



<p>But wait, there&#8217;s a twist! Rumor has it that the iPhone 15 Pro Max might be fashionably late to the party, possibly showing up in October. And oh, Apple might give it a fancy new name, from &#8220;Max&#8221; to &#8220;Ultra.&#8221; Ooh la la!</p>



<p>Now, let&#8217;s talk about the juicy stuff—the iPhone 15 features. While it might not be a total game-changer, it&#8217;s still packing some heat. Unlike its rivals who are bringing back fingerprint sensors, Apple&#8217;s sticking to its guns. But it&#8217;s got a shiny new A17 bionic chip under the hood, a 3 nanometer powerhouse by TSMC, promising better battery life.</p>



<p>The Pro models are flexing with a titanium frame, ditching the old stainless steel. Stronger and lighter &#8211; that&#8217;s the name of the game. Plus, say goodbye to the &#8220;notch&#8221; and hello to an adaptive display around a punch-hole camera. Nomura&#8217;s whispering that the cameras in the entry-level iPhone 15 and 15 Plus are getting a major upgrade, while the Pro models are adding a &#8220;periscope&#8221; lens for some epic zooming action. Cameras are the real stars here, folks!</p>



<p>Leaked renders are spilling the beans about a bigger camera bump on the back and a slightly curved glass screen. Oh, and that mute button? It&#8217;s making way for a snazzy &#8220;action&#8221; button you can customize for all your needs.</p>



<p>But the fun doesn&#8217;t stop there. iOS 17, the iPhone&#8217;s new operating system, is joining the party too. It&#8217;s bringing a journal app for all you writers out there. Time to pen down those thoughts!</p>



<p>Now, let&#8217;s talk cables. The charging game is changing, folks. Thanks to an EU law, Apple&#8217;s ditching its trusty lightning cables for USB-C. It&#8217;s faster, but it might mean saying goodbye to your old cables. Apple&#8217;s making this switch worldwide, not just in the EU.</p>



<p>And what about the Apple Watch? Brace yourselves for the Apple Watch Series 9 with a beefed-up processor. As for the sporty Apple Watch Ultra, we&#8217;ll have to wait and see if it gets an upgrade.</p>



<p>With USB-C making waves, there are rumors about an AirPods revamp too. At least the charging case might get a makeover.</p>



<p>But hold your horses if you&#8217;re waiting for Apple&#8217;s VR headset, the Vision Pro. It got a teaser earlier, but the real deal won&#8217;t drop until next year.</p>



<p>Now, let&#8217;s talk money. The iPhone 15&#8217;s price tag is still a mystery, but brace yourselves, it might burn a slightly bigger hole in your pocket. The iPhone 14 wasn&#8217;t exactly a bargain, and analysts at Barclays are hinting at an even steeper price hike. Expect the iPhone 15 Pro to jump by around a hundred bucks, and the Pro Max to climb between one and two hundred dollars higher. Ouch!</p>



<p>But hey, in the ever-evolving world of tech, sometimes you got to pay the price for staying on the cutting edge. So, gear up, tech enthusiasts, because Apple&#8217;s about to drop some serious tech thunder, and we can&#8217;t wait! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f4f1.png" alt="📱" class="wp-smiley"  /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f4a5.png" alt="💥" class="wp-smiley"  /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>The Google vs. United States Antitrust Litigation Google Faces a Major Challenge in Landmark Antitrust Trial</title>
			<link>https://user2023.r-project.org/news/tech/the-google-vs-united-states-antitrust-litigation-google-faces-a-major-challenge-in-landmark-antitrust-trial/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 06:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://user2023.r-project.org/?p=24</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[Google, the tech giant that has long dominated the world of internet search, is now...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://user2023.r-project.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/google-antitrust.webp" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>Google, the tech giant that has long dominated the world of internet search, is now confronting a significant threat to its empire. Federal regulators are set to launch a monumental antitrust trial—the most significant in a quarter-century—in an effort to dismantle Google&#8217;s internet dominance. The trial, which is expected to span the next ten weeks, will see federal lawyers and state attorneys general working together to prove that Google has manipulated the market to its advantage by establishing its search engine as the default choice in numerous locations and on various devices. U.S. District Judge Amit Mehta will likely deliver a ruling in early the following year. If Google is found to have violated the law, another trial will determine the necessary measures to restrain the Mountain View, California-based company.</p>



<p>In a courtroom filled with top executives from Google and its parent company, Alphabet Inc., as well as representatives from other tech powerhouses, including Alphabet CEO Sundar Pichai, key discussions will revolve around whether Google&#8217;s practices have indeed stifled competition. Court documents suggest that even high-ranking Apple executive Eddy Cue might be called to testify.</p>



<p>The roots of this legal battle trace back almost three years when the Justice Department filed an antitrust lawsuit against Google during the Trump administration. The suit alleges that Google has exploited its internet search dominance to gain an unfair edge over competitors. Government lawyers argue that Google maintains its dominance through a form of payola, investing billions of dollars each year to secure its position as the default search engine on the iPhone and on web browsers like Apple’s Safari and Mozilla’s Firefox.</p>



<p>Regulators also assert that Google has manipulated the market by requiring device manufacturers to bundle its search engine with Android software for smartphones in exchange for full access to the Android app store.</p>



<p>Google, however, counters that it faces substantial competition despite controlling approximately 90% of the internet search market. The company argues that its rivals range from search engines like Microsoft&#8217;s Bing to e-commerce giants like Amazon and review platforms like Yelp, where users can seek recommendations or information.</p>



<p>From Google&#8217;s perspective, its continuous enhancements to the search engine explain why users keep returning, making &#8220;Googling&#8221; synonymous with online searches.</p>



<p>The trial&#8217;s timing is significant, aligning with the 25th anniversary of Google&#8217;s first investment—a $100,000 check from Sun Microsystems co-founder Andy Bechtolsheim. This initial investment allowed Larry Page and Sergey Brin to establish Google in a Silicon Valley garage. Today, Alphabet, Google&#8217;s parent company, boasts a market value of $1.7 trillion and employs 182,000 people. The majority of its revenue stems from the $224 billion generated through annual ad sales, facilitated by a network of digital services centered around a search engine fielding billions of daily queries.</p>



<p>The antitrust case against Google bears a striking resemblance to the one brought against Microsoft in 1998. Regulators accused Microsoft of compelling computer manufacturers reliant on its dominant Windows operating system to feature Microsoft&#8217;s Internet Explorer, effectively stifling competition from the once-popular Netscape browser as the internet gained mainstream prominence.</p>



<p>Notably, some members of the Justice Department&#8217;s team in the Google case, including lead litigator Kenneth Dintzer, previously worked on the Microsoft investigation.</p>



<p>The outcome of this trial could significantly impact Google. One possibility is that Google may be compelled to cease payments to companies like Apple, which have made Google the default search engine on their devices. Alternatively, the legal battle might divert Google&#8217;s focus, as it did with Microsoft following its antitrust confrontation with the Justice Department. Distracted by legal battles, Microsoft struggled to adapt to the evolving landscape of internet search and smartphones, providing Google with an opportunity to transition from a startup to a formidable industry leader.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>GlobalFoundries Launches $4 Billion Chip Factory in Singapore</title>
			<link>https://user2023.r-project.org/news/business/globalfoundries-launches-4-billion-chip-factory-in-singapore/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 06:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://user2023.r-project.org/?p=21</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[GlobalFoundries, the third-largest company that makes computer chips for others, opened a new semiconductor factory...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://user2023.r-project.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/GlobalFoundries.webp" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>GlobalFoundries, the third-largest company that makes computer chips for others, opened a new semiconductor factory in Singapore. This is part of their plan to make more things around the world.</p>



<p>The new factory is quite big, about 23,000 square meters, which is about 248,000 square feet. When it&#8217;s fully ready in 2025 or 2026, it will make 450,000 round plates of silicon every year. These plates are called &#8220;wafers.&#8221; This factory will also give jobs to 1,000 people, said Tan Yew Kong, who is the boss of GlobalFoundries in Singapore.</p>



<p>Tan Yew Kong also said, &#8220;If we use this factory as much as we can, it will make about 45% of all the money GlobalFoundries gets.&#8221; He also thinks that more people will want to buy computer chips in the second half of 2024.</p>



<p>GlobalFoundries also has two other factories in Singapore. They make even more wafers &#8211; 720,000 big ones and 692,000 smaller ones. These wafers go into making things like cars and 5G technology.</p>



<p>GlobalFoundries said in 2021 that they will spend $6 billion to build more factories because there weren&#8217;t enough computer chips during the pandemic. But now there are too many chips.</p>



<p>One of the big companies that buys chips from GlobalFoundries is Qualcomm. They said on Monday that they made a deal with Apple.</p>



<p>GlobalFoundries is the third biggest company that makes chips for others. The top two are TSMC in Taiwan and Samsung in South Korea, according to a company that studies the chip market.</p>



<p>Singapore makes 11% of all the computer chips in the world. More companies will start making chips there in the next few months.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>China&#8217;s Bid to Widen iPhone Ban: Impact on Tech Industry</title>
			<link>https://user2023.r-project.org/news/tech/chinas-bid-to-widen-iphone-ban-impact-on-tech-industry/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 06:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://user2023.r-project.org/?p=18</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[China plans to expand a ban on the use of iPhones in sensitive departments to...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://user2023.r-project.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/China-iPhone-Ban.webp" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>China plans to expand a ban on the use of iPhones in sensitive departments to government-backed agencies and state companies, a sign of growing challenges for Apple Inc. in its biggest foreign market and global production base.</p>



<p>Several agencies have begun instructing staff not to bring their iPhones to work, people familiar with the matter said, affirming a previous report from the Wall Street Journal. In addition, Beijing intends to extend that restriction far more broadly to a plethora of state-owned enterprises and other government-controlled organizations, said the people, who asked not to be identified discussing a sensitive matter.</p>



<p>If Beijing goes ahead, the unprecedented blockade will be the culmination of a yearslong effort to root out foreign technology use in sensitive environments, coinciding with Beijing’s effort to reduce its reliance on American software and circuitry. It threatens to erode Apple’s position in a market that yields about a fifth of its revenue, and from where it makes the majority of the world’s iPhones through sprawling factories that employ millions of Chinese.</p>



<p>It’s unclear how many companies or agencies could eventually adopt restrictions on personal devices, and there’s been no formal or written injunction as yet, the people said. State firms or organizations will likely vary in how strictly they enforce such bans, with some forbidding Apple devices from the workplace while others could bar employees from using them entirely.</p>



<p>Chinese state firms like oil giant PetroChina Co. employ millions and control vast swathes of a centrally planned economy. Given Apple’s relationship with Beijing and its importance to the economy, it “has historically been viewed as relatively safe in China from government restrictions,” KeyBanc Capital Markets analyst Brandon Nispel said in a report Wednesday. “Is the government changing its stance?”</p>



<p>A representative for Cupertino, California-based Apple didn’t respond to a request for comment. The State-Owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission and the State Council Information Office didn’t respond to faxed requests for comment.</p>



<p>Apple shares fell 2.9% Thursday in New York, following a 3.6% decline on Wednesday — their biggest single-day drop since Aug. 4. European chipmakers, including Apple supplier STMicroelectronics NV, also declined on Thursday.</p>



<p>Read More: Apple’s 2-Day Slide Nears $200 Billion on China IPhone Curbs</p>



<p>Apple enjoys widespread popularity in China, despite rising resentment of American efforts to contain the Asian country’s technology industry. The company’s iPhones are among the nation’s bestsellers and are common in both the government and private sector.</p>



<p>But the blockade on the devices coincides with stepped-up efforts to develop domestic technology that can match or even surpass American innovation. Last week, the release of a Huawei Technologies Co. smartphone that contained an advanced made-in-China processor caused a stir on both sides of the Pacific. State media celebrated an early triumph against harsh US sanctions, while one US lawmaker called for an investigation into possible violations of those curbs.</p>



<p>Foreign devices have long been discouraged in sensitive agencies, particularly as Beijing escalated a campaign in recent years to reduce a reliance on technology from the US, China’s geopolitical rival.</p>



<p>Employees at “some” central government regulators received instructions via chat groups and in meetings to stop bringing such gadgets into the office, the Journal reported earlier, citing people familiar with the matter. It’s not clear how widely the orders were issued, it said.</p>



<p>Read More: China Orders Government, State Firms to Dump Foreign PCs</p>



<p>In 2022, Beijing ordered central government agencies and state-backed corporations to replace foreign-branded personal computers with domestic alternatives within two years, marking one of the most aggressive efforts to eradicate key overseas technology from within its most sensitive organs.</p>



<p>The Biden administration, meanwhile, has sought to limit exports of cutting-edge semiconductor equipment to China. And China’s top chipmaker, Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp., has come under scrutiny for supplying components to Huawei — a company the US has blacklisted.</p>



<p>Read More: SMIC’s Huawei Chip May Violate Sanctions, US Lawmaker Says</p>



<p>Even with US-China ties fraying, Apple remains highly dependent on the Asian country — both as a manufacturing partner and a market for its products. Chief Executive Officer Tim Cook celebrated that relationship during a trip to China earlier this year, calling it “symbiotic.”</p>



<p>China also was one of the highlights of Apple’s results last quarter, helping offset a generally sluggish period. The company is preparing to unveil its latest iPhones next week, setting the stage for a holiday quarter that is invariably its biggest sales period of the year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Viewers Are Shocked by How Much the Winners of the US Open 2023 Earned</title>
			<link>https://user2023.r-project.org/news/sports/viewers-are-shocked-by-how-much-the-winners-of-the-us-open-2023-earned/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 06:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://user2023.r-project.org/?p=15</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[The 2023 US Open final unfolded as an epic battle, showcasing the relentless determination of...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://user2023.r-project.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/Winners-of-the-US-Open-2023.webp" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>The 2023 US Open final unfolded as an epic battle, showcasing the relentless determination of seasoned champions defending their legacies and the emergence of a new generation eager to etch their names into tennis history. Dive into the exhilarating world of this year&#8217;s victors, and discover the incredible rewards awaiting those who ascend to the pinnacle of the sport.</p>



<p><strong>Who Seized Glory in the 2023 US Open Women&#8217;s Championship?</strong><br>In a stunning display of skill and poise, American prodigy Coco Gauff outshone her competition, besting Aryna Sabalenka in the thrilling US Open singles final on September 9. This triumph marked the inception of a highly promising Grand Slam career for Gauff, as she claimed her maiden title in dramatic fashion.</p>



<p>Reflecting on her victory, Gauff humbly remarked, &#8220;I find myself in a state of disbelief at this moment. I believe that the challenges and trials we face are part of a greater plan, making this achievement even more profound.&#8221;</p>



<p><strong>The Magnificent Conquest of the 2023 US Open Men&#8217;s Championship</strong><br>In the men&#8217;s singles, Serbian tennis virtuoso Novak Djokovic demonstrated his unparalleled prowess by overcoming Russian sensation Daniil Medvedev on September 10. Djokovic&#8217;s victory served as a redemption arc, erasing the memory of his defeat to Medvedev in the 2021 US Open. With this triumph, Djokovic now boasts an astonishing 24 Grand Slam titles, a record-equalling achievement that etches his name indelibly in tennis history.</p>



<p>Expressing his elation, Djokovic stated, &#8220;This victory means the world to me. I am living out my childhood dream, competing at the highest echelon of this sport, which has provided my family and me with immeasurable blessings. While I never envisioned this moment, the past few years convinced me that I had a shot at making history. When an opportunity like this presents itself, why not seize it?&#8221;</p>



<p><strong>The Lucrative Rewards of Victory at the 2023 US Open</strong><br>As the triumphant champions in the men&#8217;s and women&#8217;s singles categories, Djokovic and Gauff were each bestowed with a substantial prize of $3 million USD. This remarkable achievement propels Djokovic&#8217;s career earnings to an astonishing £175 million, securing his position atop the rankings with a substantial $40 million lead over Rafael Nadal.</p>



<p><strong>Rewarding Excellence Across the Board</strong><br>In acknowledgment of their remarkable performances, the runners-up in the singles categories, Daniil Medvedev and Aryna Sabalenka, received well-earned compensation of $350,000 for their efforts at the US Open. Meanwhile, the highly competitive semifinalists were awarded $180,000, and the tenacious quarterfinalists each claimed a commendable prize of $100,000. Such generous rewards illustrate the value placed on excellence in the world of professional tennis, motivating athletes to push their limits and pursue greatness.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Drew McIntyre Teases WWE Fans with CM Punk&#8217;s Return Speculation</title>
			<link>https://user2023.r-project.org/news/entertainment/drew-mcintyre-teases-wwe-fans-with-cm-punks-return-speculation/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 05:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://user2023.r-project.org/?p=11</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[AEW made a bold move by parting ways with the former AEW World Champion, CM...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://user2023.r-project.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/Drew-McIntyre.webp" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>AEW made a bold move by parting ways with the former AEW World Champion, CM Punk, on September 2, following a backstage incident involving Jack Perry at AEW All In. CM Punk, known for his remarkable six-time world champion legacy with WWE, left the wrestling world in 2014, only to return with a bang in 2021, stirring up controversy during his tenure with AEW. Now, as a free agent, the wrestling community is abuzz with speculation about his potential WWE comeback.</p>



<p>In an exclusive interview with Riju Dasgupta of Sportskeeda, Drew McIntyre weighed in on the possibility of sharing the ring with CM Punk in WWE:</p>



<p>&#8220;While I don&#8217;t have the authority to make such decisions,&#8221; Drew McIntyre began, &#8220;I choose my words carefully in interviews. However, there&#8217;s no denying that CM Punk is a polarizing figure who sparks conversations. I&#8217;ll leave it at that.&#8221;</p>



<p>Zelina Vega, another prominent figure in the wrestling world, also expressed her thoughts on the prospect of CM Punk&#8217;s WWE return in an interview with Newsday:</p>



<p>Full video here: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G8nNd0Eqieg">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G8nNd0Eqieg</a></p>



<p>&#8220;Wouldn&#8217;t it be incredible to see him back in the WWE? Absolutely,&#8221; Zelina Vega exclaimed. &#8220;I might not be privy to all the details of his AEW situation, but I&#8217;ve always had a wonderful relationship with CM Punk. I firmly believe in not letting rumors and external opinions cloud your judgment. People are multi-faceted, and when you delve deeper into a person&#8217;s core, that&#8217;s where the true essence lies. In my experience, Punk has been nothing short of exceptional. So, could the &#8216;X&#8217; signify him crossing paths with Dominik? Absolutely, because I&#8217;m an ardent supporter of his, and he&#8217;s always been there for me.&#8221;</p>



<p>As we await what the future holds for CM Punk, one thing is certain: his potential return to WWE has ignited a fire of anticipation among fans, and the wrestling world eagerly watches and speculates.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
<!-- last GN Pub feeds fetch (not specifically this feed): has not fetched -->